

Profile

Highly experienced Senior Cloud Engineer with over ten years of experience in analysing, designing, developing, and managing applications. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Adept in carefully diagnosing and assessing issues, and offering real viable solutions using AWS, Microsoft Azure and middle-ware technologies (IBM ACE, IBM MQ).

Employment History

Senior Engineer, Sainsburys Supermarkets, London

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

Developed a DevOps strategy that increased the speed and reliability of application deployment

Transforming the Legacy Application Infrastructure code to adhere to latest standards and version

Implemented automation processes that reduced manual tasks by 80%, allowing for faster deployment of new cloud resources

Migrated the Jenkins Code to GitHub Actions to adhere to cost optimisation

Created the Infrastructure code from scratch for old Legacy application

Senior DevOps Engineer, TATA Consultancy Services, London

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2022

Delivered the Integration Solutions built on top of Microsoft Technologies Azure (IaaS, PaaS, Hybrid)

Worked on end-end design for Cloud Migration projects on both laaS and PaaS Model

Hands-on experience in Docker containerisation and Kubernetes Expertise in CI/CD automation using Jenkins, Terraform, Docker

Migrated on-premise integration workload to Azure cloud

Delivered B2B solutions capability on Azure by building multiple File-

Gateway and API patterns on Azure

Managing both Unmanaged and Managed(Kubernetes) containerized platform

Resourceful on Azure Infra components creation like VNET, SUBNET, NSG, VM, RG, Storage Account, Key-Vault, ILB, etc., using Terraform and Jenkins

Building IBM integration products capability on containerization (Docker Images)

Senior Integration Engineer, TATA Consultancy Services, Chennai

MARCH 2017 - JANUARY 2019

Present strategies, specifications for seamless migration from IBM

WebSphere Message Broker into IBM Integration Bus Infrastructure.

Engaged in automated deployment solution design and implementation based on problem statement of the client with industry standards

Details

London United Kingdom +44 7438 867 877 nandakumar649@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Amazon Web Services (IaaS, CaaS)

Docker Containerization

Terraform

GitHub Actions

Jenkins

Ansible

Agile methodologies

Microsoft Technologies Azure (IaaS, PaaS, Hybrid)

Azure Compute, Network, Storage & Disaster Recovery

Kubernetes

IBM App Connect Enterprise

IBM WebSphere MQ

Mule ESB

Applied automated testing solutions for unit, integration and system testing

Worked closely with customers and other Business stakeholders to

determine planning, implementation, and integration of system-oriented projects

Implemented performance improvement operations for existing functional designs and recommended integration solutions

An accomplished milestone to facilitate auto replay feature in exception handling framework for support engineers

Integration Designer, TATA Consultancy Services, London

JULY 2015 - FEBRUARY 2017

Anchored deliverables including presentations, function design documents and Data Object Mapping Documents

Designed, Implemented Integration solutions for Automated Warehouse Management and Logistics Movement

Implemented API based Solution for Stock Management and Replenishment

Integration Developer, TATA Consultancy Services, Chennai

2012 - JULY 2015

Designed, developed Integration patterns for on-demand services with Master Data Management systems.

Integrated Demand & Fulfilment systems to Store Management Systems to ensure real-time replenishment of products.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, R.M.K Engineering College, Chennai

APRIL 2008 - APRIL 2012